# SUBHASH TALLURI

480-410-0824

subhash.talluri@hotmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Trained mechanical engineer. Experienced Aerospace engineer. Passionate data scientist. IoT Enthusiast

#### **SKILLS**

Data Science - Python, R, SQL, Full stack development, Tableau, Hadoop Ecosystem Engineering - Ansys, LS-Dyna, Hypermesh, Abacus, Catia, Solid works, PTC Creo

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## **Cyient Insights**

Data Scientist

Chandler, AZ | Oct 2017 - Present

- Experienced in providing predictive analytics solutions for the aerospace industry
- Expertise in engine health monitoring, aircraft systems health monitoring, advanced engine diagnostics and prognostics
- Adept at data wrangling, machine learning and data visualization
- Led a team of remote data scientists to develop and validate predictive models and feature engineering scripts.

#### **Pratt & Whitney Canada**

Analyst, Material/Structural

Mississau ga, Ontario | Dec 2010 - Sept 2017

- · Experienced in gas turbine engine development from concept design, first engine test, certification and production phase
- Specialist in design, stress analysis, thermal analysis, dynamic analysis, impact analysis, fracture mechanics, fatigue life evaluation, MRB activities, structural testing and root cause investigation
- Expert in structural & dynamic analysis for extreme loading conditions such as fan blade off, bird ingestion, rotor containment, windmill & maneuver conditions
- Supported field hardware during engine overhauls, inspection & maintenance intervals with quick turnaround times. Reviewed deviation in hardware against engineering definition and assessed their impact on durability and strength
- Expertise in full engine & component rig tests to support internal engine development, analytical methods validation, research and to address production or field issues.
- Experienced in writing certification reports for regulating authorities such as Transport Canada, FAA & EASA

#### **Software Techniques Inc.**

FEA Analyst / Programmer

Mississauga, Ontario | May 2010 - Nov 2010

- Worked with a team to develop a standalone MATLAB application for a leading firm in the oil & gas industry
- · Modeled oil well drill string vibrations using finite element methods, Lagrange dynamics and rock mechanics from scratch

### **EDUCATION**

University Degrees	University	Year
MS, Computer Science	University of Illinois Urbana Champaign	2018
MS, Aerospace Science & Engineering	University of Toronto	2010
BS, Mechanical Engineering	Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University	2008

#### Academic Experience, Data Science

Mississauga, Ontario | Aug 2016 - April 2018

- Predicting Borrower Risk, Lending Club Data Developed a novel method of predicting borrower risk through augmented data using logistic regression & Naïve Bayes. Model proved to be better than Lending club's base model accuracy.
- *Product Recommendation, Instacart Data* Developed a dynamic web application for Instacart data using PostgreSQL db, Python middleware and JavaScript-Bootstrap front end. Used Py-spark and k-means clustering for product recommendations
- Applied Machine Learning Projects Developed Naïve Bayes classifier and SVM from scratch. Used PCA, Boltzmann Machines, Expectation Maximization and Convolutional neural networks for image classification.

#### **Academic Experience, Engineering**

Toronto, Ontario | Aug 2008 - April 2010

- Intern, Integrity Testing Laboratory Inc Laboratory analysis of materials exposed to space environment
- Structures Lead, Space Flight Lab, Univ. of Toronto Subsystem design of solar sail satellite
- Research Project, Univ. of Toronto Engine-out autopilot design of Boeing 747
- Research Project, Univ of Toronto Analysis of propulsive characteristics of ram-rocket under design